63 Pointe Rok Drive ◊ Worcester, Ma. 01604 Home (508)797-3916 \$\times\$ Mobile (508)868-7831 stevensantora@live.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:

Savvy, results oriented procurement professional with extensive experience, and proven success in internal and external negotiations. Facilitated the best possible prices, quality, service and lead times. Displays exceptional interpersonal skills with a very strong work ethic and the ability to tackle and master projects and responsibilities. Provided training to materials personnel to keep up-to-date records. manage ERP and vendors for quality, lead times and prices while working in a union and non-union environment. Developed and implemented a professional atmosphere that would ultimately open better communications and relationships with vendors/suppliers through site visits. Commodity focus included machine tools, Machine shops, metal structures, electro-mechanical components/sub systems, sheet metal, castings,

EXPERIENCE:

Part and Temporary positions Retail Sales 2008 to Present

Applied Analytics Inc. Industrial Controls Concord, MA 2010 to 2010

- Purchasing Manager / Shipping Manager Temp Contractor
- Sourced vendors for outside manufacturing of cable and electronics assemblies sheet metal and machining to reduce cost and quality of incoming materials.
- Negotiated annually contracts with suppliers, vendors, and internal; management to attain the lowest possible price including site audits.
- Procured material for electro-mechanical Assemblies, electronics, sheet metal and machining enclosures.
- Negotiated cost savings of 25% to 40% in freight while consolidating shipments.

Communications Test Design, Inc. Telecommunications Westborough, MA Procurement Supervisor/Sr. Buyer 2000 to 2008 Temp to Perm

- Trained and managed other purchasing professionals to perform their functions with skill and technique.
- Prepared and analyzed bid evaluations for services.
- Negotiated, renegotiated, and administered contracts with suppliers, vendors, and internal; management/departments to attain the lowest possible price including site visits.
- Planned supported and procured material for electro-mechanical materials, steel structures and enclosures.
- Negotiated cost savings of 25% to 40% in freight while consolidating shipments.

Thermal Jarrell Ash Purchasing Agent

Trace Analyzers Temp to Perm

Franklin, MA 1999 to 2000

- ♦ Interviewed vendors and visited suppliers' plants and distribution centers to examine and learn about products, services and prices.
- ♦ Attended meetings, trade shows, conferences, conventions and seminars to network with people in other purchasing departments.
- ♦ Outsourced machine parts, sheet metal and castings local and abroad.
- ♦ Evaluated and negotiated supplier delivery, lead times and product specifications.

Delta Design Electro/Mechanical Buyer Semiconductors Temp to Perm

Littleton, MA 1997 to 1999

- Implemented two bread man, KanBan programs for cost savings.
- ♦ Purchased the highest quality merchandise at the lowest possible cost. (electronic components/semi-conductor devices, electro-mechanical material, MRO)
- ♦ Monitored material changes affecting supply and demand, tracked market conditions, price trends, and futures markets.
- ♦ Updated MRP system

Electronic Space Systems Radomes & Antennas Senior Buyer

Ayer, MA 1996 to 1997

- ♦ Interviewed vendors and visited suppliers' plants and distribution centers to examine and learn about products, services and prices.
- Purchased the highest quality merchandise at the lowest possible price with quantities that would reflect least amount of inventory turns.
- Machined parts, machine shops, specialized coatings.

Prolerized NE Company Steel Recycling Purchasing Agent

Everett, MA 1985 to 1995

- Negotiated and secured guaranteed fixed pricing for futures in diesel fuel.
- Managed all maintenance contracts and procured heavy industrial commodities for equipment and buildings i.e. valves, gauges, electro-mechanical parts.

EDUCATION:

Becker College
Business Management
U Mass

Worcester, MA

Boston, MA

ADDITIONAL TRAINING:

- ♦ Oracle, SAP, Man Man X and MRP.
- ♦ Internet Explorer, MS Word/Excel, QuickBooks and Power Point.
- ♦ Blue Print Reading, ISO 9000,FAR clauses.
- International Purchasing-Low Cost Centers Vendor Management

LICENSE:

- ♦ CPP Certified Purchasing Professional 2/2008
- ♦ CPPM Certified Professional Purchasing Manager 1/2009
- ♦ CISCM Certified International Supply Chain Manager 2/2009
- ♦ Member of the American Purchasing Society 2007 to Present